'Cause every time I see your face
因为每次我看见你的脸
I can't help but fall from grace
就情不自禁地失态
This girl's good.
这女的很棒
Yeah,a song with rhyming words! I never thought of that before.
是啊，歌词押韵 我以前倒没想过
I like her.
我喜欢她
Why? Because she can both sing and play guitar at the same time?
为什么？因为她会唱歌 弹吉他，还可边弹边唱吗？
That's all I'm looking for from these people.
这正是我对表演艺人的期待
Look at you,all jealous.
看，你忌妒得要命
Come on,Pheebs. You two have completely different styles.
拜托，菲比 你们俩的风格完全不同
She's more.... You know?
她比较…你知道
And you're more....
而你比较…
Say you'll stay beside me
说你会留在我身边
See? Everybody else is happy she's done.
看到没？ 大家都很高兴她唱完了
Okay,my next song's called:
好，我接下来要唱的是…
"Phoebe Buffay,What Can I Say? I Loved When We Were...
菲比，我该怎么说？ 我很怀念当初…
...Singing Partners and I Shouldn't Have Left You That Way."
我们一起唱歌的日子 我不该那样离开你的
One of those "look for the hidden meaning" songs.
就是那种别有深意的歌
The One With Phoebe's Ex-Partner
本集播出：“菲比的旧搭档”
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河马压缩制作 本字幕为河马根据R3DVD OCR得来
Hey,Phoebe.
嘿，菲比
Hey,Leslie.
嘿，莱丝莉
How'd you know I'd be here?
你怎么知道我会在这里？
I saw Vlad at the place where they sell the big fish.
我在卖大鱼的地方看到佛拉德
He said you played here a lot,so....
她说你常在这里玩，所以…
I have to go to the bathroom.
我要上洗手间
If "big-fish place" comes up again...
如果你们又谈到“大鱼”…
... I'd like to know if that's several big fish or just one big fish.
我想知道是好几条大鱼 还是一条大鱼而已
So Phoebe says you write jingles.
菲比说你写广告歌
Actually,I said she abandoned me to write jingles.
我是说她抛弃我去写广告歌
Anything we might've heard of?
有没有我们听过的？
Home is never far away
家永远不远
Home is Homestar Stew.
回家的感觉就是家星跗
But I don't do that anymore. I got kind of sick of it.
但我已经不写了 我有点厌倦了
And then I couldn't come up with anything good,so they fired me.
再说我也写不出好东西 所以被炒鱿鱼了
Bummer.
太可惜了
Well,you know,I was just....
你知道，我只是…
I was just thinking and just hoping that...
我只是想或许…
... maybe you'd want to get back together?
也许你愿意跟我再度合作
No,but,thanks.
不了，不过，谢谢你
Come on,Phoebe. Would you just think about it?
拜托，菲比 你考虑一下好吗？
No,but,thanks.
不了，不过，谢谢你
See you,Pheebs.
再见，菲比
That was kind of brutal.
你好狠心
Let this be a lesson to all of you.
你们都要记住
Once you betray me, I become like the lce Woman.
一旦背叛我 我就成了冷血的女人
I'm just very cold,hard,unyielding.
我是铁石心肠，绝不心软
You know,nothing can penetrate this icy exterior.
任何东西都无法 穿透我这冰冷的外衣
Can I have a tissue?
给我一张面纸好吗？
Is someone in there?
里面有人吗？
I'm playing a daredevil game...
我是在玩比大胆的游戏
...called "Wait Until the Last Moment Before I Burst and Die."
叫做“等到最后一刻 然后暴毙而死”
Jeez,man! Did you fall?
老天，你跌倒…
Hi!
嗨
So did you? Did you fall high?
你…是兴奋过度吗？
Someone was in the ladies' room. I couldn't wait.
女厕所有人，我等不及了
I left the lid up for you,though.
不过我帮你把马桶盖掀起来了
You know what,Gunther? Go ahead.
这样吧，甘瑟，你先
I'm talking to....
我要跟这位…
This is where you say your name.
这时候你要报上你的名字
Ginger.
金吉儿
Ginger. I'm talking to Ginger,so...
金吉儿 我在跟甘瑟说话，所以…
Don't you have to use the bathroom?
你不必上厕所吗？
No,I just I'd rather talk to you.
不，我只是… 我宁可跟你聊天
Yes,I do.
是的
Yes,I do have to go to the bathroom.
对，我再不上就不行了
There's someone in here.
里面有人
-Where's Chandler? -He can't make it.
钱德在哪里？ 他不能去了
He said he had to go back to his job and
他说他要回去上班…
Joey?
乔伊？
Joey Tribbiani?
乔伊崔比亚尼？
I can see you,okay?
我看得到你，好吗？
You're hiding behind the coats.
你藏在外套后面
Close one.
差点就被逮到了
Hi.
嗨
Hi,sweetie.
嗨，甜心
Hello.
哈罗
Hey,Ross.
嘿，罗斯
-I've got some bad news. -What?
我有坏消息 什么坏消息？
I can eat, but I have to come back here.
我可以去吃饭 但饭后要回来加班
Come on. You've worked late every night for two weeks.
拜托，你已经连续 加班两星期了
-What is it now? -It's my fault. I quit today.
这次又有什么事？ 是我不好，我今天辞职了
But work comes first!
但工作重要
But that's sad about you,though. What happened?
但可惜你要走了 出了什么事？
What happened? Burn out? Burn all out,did you?
出了什么事？精力耗尽了 精力耗尽了是吗？
He's leaving for a better job.
他另有高就
That's great. So I guess this is goodbye then.
太好了，我想那就再见了
Goodbye.
再见
Okay,then.
好吧
Well,we're gonna miss you around here.
我们会想你的
Yeah,me too.
我也是
-So see you on Saturday. -Yeah,you bet!
星期六见 没问题
Now,you know those are a delicacy in lndia.
这是一种印度点心
That was Leslie calling to see if we can get back together.
是莱丝莉呼叫我 看我们能不能复合
It's like the 20th time today. Yeah,good luck,Leslie.
她已经打了二十次了 祝你好运，莱丝莉
She must've hurt you bad.
她一定把你伤得很重
Well,yeah. You know,we were best friends...
是啊，我们是最好的朋友
...ever since we were little. Our moms worked on the barge together.
我们从小就是好朋友 我们的母亲是游艇上的同事
You two must've been so cute, running around on a barge.
你们两个在游艇上 跑来跑去一定很可爱
You never run on a barge!
游艇上不能跑来跑去
Is Chandler around?
钱德在吗？
He met some girl at the coffeehouse.
他在咖啡厅认识一个女的
Ginger something.
金吉儿什么的
Sure it wasn't something that sounded liked Ginger? Like "Gingeer"?
你确定不是金吉儿的谐音而已 像金洁儿什么的？
No,it was Ginger.
不，是金吉儿
I remember because when he told me,I said:
我之所以记得是因为 他告诉我的时候，我说
The movie star
“电影明星”
Oh,man!
老天
That's the girl I was hiding from.
我就是在躲这个女的
When she sees he's my roommate, she'll tell him what I did.
要是知道他是我室友 一定会把我抖出来
What did you do?
你做了什么事？
Oh,no! I can't....
不，我不能…
I can't tell you. It's the most awful thing I've ever done.
我不能跟你说 我从没做过这么过份的事
Don't tell us.
别告诉我们
We'll wait till Chandler gets home. It'll be more fun that way.
等钱德回家再说，那样更好玩
It was,like,four years ago.
大概是四年前
Ginger and I had gone out a few times. Then one weekend...
金吉儿和我约了几次会 有一个周末…
...we went to her Dad's cabin...
我们到她爸爸的渡假木屋
...just me,her and her annoying little dog,Pepper.
只有们两个人 和她讨厌的小狗椒椒
That night I cooked this really romantic dinner
那天晚上 我做了一顿烛光晚餐…
You gave her food poisoning!
你给她下毒
I wish.
我才想呢
After dinner,me,her and Pepper fell asleep in front of the fire.
晚饭后，我们两个和椒椒 在炉火前面睡着了
I woke up in the middle of the night and saw the fire was dying out...
我在半夜醒来，看到火快熄了
...so I picked up a log and threw it on.
就拿起一条木柴丢进去
Or what I thought was a log.
至少我以为那是一条木柴
Oh,my God! You threw Pepper on the fire!
我的天，你把椒椒丢进火里了
I wish.
我才想呢
Another thing I probably should've told you about Ginger...
我应该告诉你们，金吉儿…
...is that she kind of has a...
她其实…
...artificial leg.
装了义肢
Oh,my God!
我的天
What did you do after you threw her leg on the fire?
你把她的腿 丢进火里之后怎么办？
I ran!
我落跑了
That's the best kiss I've had...
这是我这一生最美好的吻
...with anybody I met in a men's room.
至少凌驾 我在男厕所遇到的其他人
Actually,me too.
我也是
Foot all in the puddle!
脚踩进水坑里了
Damn! I hate that!
要命，我最讨厌这样
-You'll have to get out of those shoes. -Don't worry.
你得把鞋子脱掉 不用紧张
No,really. You're gonna freeze.
不，真的，你会冻坏的
No,I'm not.
我不会
You're not? Have you got a bionic foot?
你不会，你有仿生电子脚？
Someday. Maybe.
也许有一天会吧
Funny book?
这本书很好笑吗？
I'm just thinking about something funny I heard today.
我只是在想我今天听到的 一句很有意思的话
Mark saying, "I'll see you Saturday."
马克说“星期六见”
Yeah,at the lecture.
对，我们要去演讲
I told you last week. You said you didn't mind.
我上星期就告诉你了 你说你不介意
It's not the lecture I mind.
我不是介意那场演讲
Please tell me it's not because I'm going with Mark.
拜托，你不是因为 我要跟马克去吧？
-Well -Oh,my God!
这个嘛… 我的天
I'm sorry,but if you're not working with him anymore...
对不起 不过你们已经不是同事了
...why do you still hang out?
为什么还要混在一起
Because he's my friend.
因为他是我朋友
But do you really need another "friend"?
但你真的需要 别的“朋友”吗？
If I stop playing with Joey and Chandler,can I play with Mark?
如果我不跟乔伊和钱德玩 可以跟马克玩吗？
Is that funny? Am I suppose to be laughing?
这好笑吗？我应该笑吗？
I don't know. You thought "See you Saturday" was funny.
我不知道，你觉得 “星期六见”很好笑
Mark is in fashion.
马克也是时装业的
I like having a friend I can share this stuff with.
我喜欢有个朋友跟我分享
You guys would never go to a lecture with me.
你们这些男生 不肯跟我去听演讲
I'd love to go with you.
我很愿意跟你去
Really?
真的？
I have clothes.
我有衣服
I even pick them out.
还是我自己挑的
For all you know, I could be a fashion...
告诉你，我可以当个时装…
... monger.
摊贩
I would love for you to go with me.
我很希望你陪我去
What?
怎么了？
What should I wear? Now I'm all nervous.
我该穿什么衣服？ 这下我好紧张
You know,they say "A watched pot never beeps."
你知道，人家说 “有人看的锅子不会叫”
It's been a couple hours...
已经几个小时了…
...and she hasn't called.
她还没打
Not that I even care. I don't.
不是说我在乎，我不在乎
Why don't you just call her?
你干脆打电话给她吧
You obviously want to.
看你就知道你很想打
You think you know me so well.
你自以为很了解我
Well,don't you wanna?
你不想打吗？
So I do know you.
所以我是很了解你
That's what I said.
我就是这么说的
Well,so?
怎么样？
I can't.
我办不到
I can't. She dumped me.
我办不到，她抛弃了我
I totally trusted her, then one day it was like:
我完全相信她 然后突然有一天
"Okay,bye,Pheebs." Gone!
“好，再见，菲比” 一去不回
You know what the saddest part is?
你知道最叫人 难过的是什么吗？
When we were playing together, that was...
我们在一起 表演的时候，是我…
...the most fun I've ever had in all my lives.
永生永世最快乐的时光了
My favorite shoes,so good to me I wear them every day
我最爱的鞋子，好好穿 我每天非穿不可
Down at the heel,holes in the toes Don't care what people say
鞋底塌了，脚趾开口 不在乎别人怎么说
My feet's best friend Pals to the end
我双脚的知音 永远的好友
With them,I'm one hot chickie
穿着这双鞋 我就是性感小辣妹
Though late one night Not much light
不过有一天晚上 天色灰暗
I stepped in something icky
我采到黏黏的东西
Sticky shoes,sticky shoes
黏黏的鞋子，黏黏的鞋子
Always make me smile
永远让我破涕为笑
Sticky shoes,sticky shoes Next time I'll...
黏黏的鞋子，黏黏的鞋子 下次我要…
...avoid the...
躲开…
...pile!
泥巴堆
We're beginning to see a lot of layering of sheer fabrics and colors.
我们开始看到许多层的 谜织布料和颜色
For instance,a sheer navy blouse over a pink....
例如，一件谜织的 海军蓝衬衫搭配一件…
I'm really glad we came.
我很高兴我们来听演讲
You're so pretty.
你好美
I love you.
我爱你
Smelly cat,smelly cat
臭臭猫，臭臭猫
What are they feeding you?
他们拿什么给你吃？
Smelly cat,smelly cat
臭臭猫，臭臭猫
It's not your fault
这不是你的错
That's great!
太棒了
You know,you could totally sell this.
这首歌可以拿去卖
It'd be perfect for,like, a kitty-litter campaign.
非常适合用来…促销猫沙
A jingle?
广告歌？
Why not? You'd make a ton of money.
有何不可？可以赚大钱
If I was in this for the money, I'd be a millionaire by now.
如果我是为了赚钱 早就是百万富翁了
You gotta get out of that jingle-head.
你得把广告歌这种事给忘了
You're right. You're right. I'm sorry.
你说得对…对不起
That's okay.
没关系
I'm gonna play a song now that's really,really sad.
我现在要唱一首非常哀伤的歌
It's called "Magician Box Mix-Up."
叫做“魔术箱搞混了”
Oversized bracelets, oversized earrings...
特大号的手镯，特大号的耳环
...oversizing of accessories, in general,is very popular now.
一般来说，特大号的配件 是今年的主流
Can I borrow this? My milk's gone bad.
可以借我吗？ 我的牛奶坏了
I hate that.
我不喜欢这样
I once had a thing of half-and-half. Stole my car.
我以前很喜欢跟人家对分 所以偷了人家的车来开
So how was your date with Ginger?
你跟金吉儿的约会怎么样了？
Great.
太棒了
It was great. She's....
很棒，她…
She's great. Great looks and personality. Greatness.
她很棒，长得漂亮 性情好，无可挑剔
Sounds like she's got the...
看样子她很…
...whole package.
完整
Joey told you about the leg,huh?
乔伊跟你说过那条腿的事了？
Oh,God! It freaked me out.
吓死我了
It shouldn't,but it did.
不应该这样才对，但这是真的
I wanna keep seeing her, but it's like:
我喜欢她，想跟她交往下去 不过我忍不住…
"Hey,you know what? Where's your leg?"
“褚的，你的腿呢？”
I'm the smallest person in the world, aren't l?
我是全世界最渺小的人，是吧 我是全世界最渺小的人
Morning.
早安
Actually,he's the smallest person in the world.
其实他才是全世界最渺小的人
Heard about the leg-burning,huh?
听过火烧腿的事了吧
It came up.
她提过
Listen,I know it's a long shot,but...
我知道机会渺茫，可是…
... by any chance, did she find that funny?
她觉得这件事好笑吗？
So I nodded off a little!
我是打了一下瞌睡
"Nodded off"? Ross,you were snoring!
打瞌睡？ 罗斯，你还打呼
My father's boat didn't make that much noise when it hit rocks!
我爸爸的船撞上岩石的时候 都没有这么大声
Come on! Forty-five minutes....
拜托，45分钟
Forty-five minutes,the man talked about strappy-backed dresses.
那个人讲了45分钟的 露背吊带裙
Okay,how about four hours in a freezing museum auditorium...
好，那在冰冷的博物馆礼堂 坐上四个小时…
...Iistening to Professor "Pitstains" say:
听皮兹坦教授说…
"Remember that thing that died a gazillion years ago?
“记得这东西是 亿万年前死的吗？”
Well,here's a little bone we didn't know it had!"
“我们过去不知道 它有这块小骨头”
First of all,it's Professor Pitain.
首先，那是皮坦教授
And second of all, that little bone proved that...
其次，那块小骨头证明了…
...that particular dinosaur had wings but didn't fly.
那只恐龙有翅膀，可是不会飞
Okay,you know what I just heard?
好，你知道 我听到的是什么吗？
A hundred million people went to see a movie about what I do.
一亿人跑去看一部 以我的工作为主题的电影
I wonder how many people would go see a movie called Jurassic Parka.
我不知道有多少人会去看 一部叫“侏罗纪公园”的电影
Oh,that is so
那实在是…
A bunch of out-of-control jackets take over an island!
一群抓狂的疯子控制整个小岛
If what I do is so lame...
如果我的工作这么愚蠢
...then why did you insist on coming with me this morning?
你干嘛坚持今天早上要陪我去
Was it so I just wouldn't go with Mark?
这样我就不会跟马克去吗？
I wanted to be with you.
我想跟你在一起
I don't know,I feel like lately...
我不知道，我最近觉得…
...you're slipping away from me...
你离我越来越远…
...with this new job and all these new people.
你有了新工作，认识了新朋友
And you've got this whole other life going on.
你的人生多采多姿
I know it's dumb...
我知道这很愚蠢
...but I just hate that I'm not a part of it.
但我痛恨不能参与你的生活
It's not dumb.
这并不愚蠢
But maybe it's okay that you're not a part of it.
但也许你不能参与也不要紧
You know what I mean?
你懂我的意思吗？
I mean,it's like...
我是说…
... I like that you're not involved in that part of my life.
我不希望你参与 我在这方面的生活
That's a little clearer.
这样就清楚一点了
See,it doesn't mean I don't love you...
你看，这不表示我不爱你
... because I do. I love you so much.
因为我是爱你的 我非常爱你
But my work It's for me,you know?
但我的工作 是属于我的，你知道吗？
I'm out there on my own, and I'm doing it.
我独立自主、努力投入
And it's scary, but I love it because it's mine.
这很可怕，但我很过瘾 因为这是属于我的
But I mean,is that okay?
但我是说，这样可以吧？
Sure.
当然
You're thinking about my leg.
你在想我的腿
Actually,I forgot. What's the deal with that again?
其实我已经忘了 那是怎么回事？
Look,it's okay if it bothers you.
听我说，如果你介意也不要紧
I only need to know how much it bothers you...
我只需要知道 你介意到什么程度
...because I don't like wasting my time.
因为我不喜欢浪费时间
Am I wasting my time?
我在浪费时间吗？
No,I don't think so.
不，我想没有
It's like anything else. You just have to get used to it.
这也没什么 只要习惯就好了
What's that?
那是什么？
That's my "nubbin."
那是我的“结结”
What's a nubbin?
结结是什么？
It's kind of a third-nipple kind of thing.
就好像是第三个乳头
You have three nipples?
你有三个乳头？
Well,you know,two regulars...
有两个正常的…
...and one that barely qualifies as a
还有一个算不上是…
What?
什么？
Nothing. You know,l....
没什么，我…
I just remembered. I have to leave.
我想起来了，我该走了
You have to leave? Now? How come?
你要走？现在…？为什么？
Well,it's nubbin. Nothing!
结结，不，没什么
You know what? I'll see you later.
这样吧，再连络
I thought you weren't coming.
我还以为你不来了
-Where were you? -Come here,come here.
你到哪里去了 过来…
Don't get mad,okay?
不要生气，好吗？
Don't give me a reason to get mad, okay?
不要让我生气，好吗？
I played Smelly Cat for my old ad agency. They went nuts!
我把“臭臭猫”唱给 旧广告公司听，他们爱死了
I told you I didn't want you to try and sell it...
我说过我不要你拿去卖
...and you just big,fat did it anyway!
你这个大肥猫还是做了
I think,five years ago, I probably would have done anything...
我想五年前 我恐怕会不计一切…
...to play with you.
只求能跟你一起表演
But I can do it myself. If I can't trust you,then forget it.
但我自己还是可以唱 如果我不能信任你，就拆伙吧
I don't wanna forget it.
我不想拆伙
You know what? You have to choose.
这样吧，你必须做个选择
If the most important thing on the planet to you...
如果你觉得世界上最重要的…
...is this cat-poopy thing, then you can have Smelly Cat.
是抄袭我的歌 那“臭臭猫”就送给你
But we won't be partners.
但我们以后再也不是搭档
So what's it gonna be?
你决定怎么样？
-Smelly cat,smelly cat -Problem odor in the litter box?
臭臭猫，臭臭猫 猫沙箱有臭味？
Don't change your kitty, change your kitty litter.
不要换你的猫 换你的猫沙
It's not your fault
这不是你的错
Sorry,Pheebs.
对不起，菲比
You okay?
你没事吧？
I actually am.
我没事
Because,you know,life's gonna hand you all kinds of stuff.
因为生命中会发生各种遭遇
You learn your little lessons and hopefully you grow.
得到教训以后，希望可以成长
-You wanna hear a new song? -We'd love to.
要听新歌吗？ 太好了
Jingle bitch screwed me over
广告婊子又来搞我
Go to hell,jingle whore
去死吧，广告婊子
Go to hell,go to hell,go to hell
去死吧…
That's all I have so far.
我只写了这么多
Well,hello!
哈罗
-Where you been? -The doctor.
你到哪里去了？ 医院
Is everything okay?
一切都顺利吧？
Just had me a little nubbin-ectomy.
只是动了结结切除术
Two nipples,no waiting.
两个乳头，说做就做
Well! Just like Rachel in high school.
跟瑞秋在高中的时候一样
What?
什么？
Come on,I was kidding! It was such an obvious joke.
拜托，我是开玩笑的 一听就知道是个笑话
That was an obvious joke.
的确一听就是个笑话
And I didn't think of it. Why?
可是我没听出来，为什么？
The source of all my powers.
我才华的来源
Oh,dear God,what have I done?
老天，我做了什么事？